Stefan Nowak

% +447523221211 in LinkedIn Personal Website (C) GitHub I want to work for a company that... Current role Backend/Full-stack Software Engineer at has solved, or will solve, a real problem (good producttails.com market fit) whatever the industry or domain - with kind, Experience Pets, B2C, Consumer Goods, D2C, intelligent, curious and ethical people from a multitude eCommerce, Retail, Food, Manufacturing, of backgrounds and cultures. Education, Training, B2B **Technologies** CSS, JavaScript, Python, GraphQL, Vue.js, MySQL, Flask, REST API, MongoDB, AWS, HTML, Git

Work experience

Backend/Full-stack Software Engineer, tails.com

Oct 2019 - Present (3y 3m)

Individually-bespoke, D2C, tailored pet food eCommerce firm Pets · B2C · Consumer Goods · D2C · eCommerce · Retail · Food · Manufacturing

CSS JavaScript

Pytho

GraphQL

Vue.js

MySQL

Flask

REST API

- Replaced the legacy Flask and proprietary JS framework-based customer dashboard and delivery
 management pages with a bespoke VueJS frontend app with NGINX ingress and served by NodeJS, and built
 supporting REST APIs on the backend.
- Supported product launches and international expansion into 10 new European markets, solving complex integration and localisation issues.
- Implemented numerous (>10) targeted Optimizely A/B tests with Heap tracking to drive OKRs, such as improving the churn save rate with bespoke offers in the cancellation flow, delivery management pages, increasing shop page traffic, etc.
- Shipped a new customer orientation "tutorial space" built in VueJS
- Shipped a totally redesigned cancellation and pause flow which offers helpful alternatives and targeted
 offers to boost retention.
- Supported the transition from AWS EC2 Python monolith to EKS Kubernetes-based, multi-language GraphQL microservices architecture.

Developer and Python Content Author (Part-time Contractor), Enki Labs, Inc.

Jun 2017 - Aug 2018 (1y 2m)

Enki is a VC-backed, personalised training EdTech startup Education · Training · B2B · B2C

MongoDB

AWS

CSS

HTML

JavaScript

Git

- Wrote much of the Advanced Python I and II curriculum lessons.
- Acted as primary front-line client support during challenging scaling phases.
- Gained practical experience with production IBM Compose, AWS and MongoDB deployments, monolithic (Cordova) TestFlight apps and git repositories.

Education

King's College London, University of London

Sep 2015 - Aug 2019 (3y 11m)

Integrated Masters MSc. (i.) Hons. 4 year (First Class Honours) Computer Science

- An advanced 4-year degree program equivalent to a combined BSc. and MSc.
- Included the successful completion of two group software projects and two dissertations at BSc. and MSc. level attaining 86% and 96% respectively.
- Won the 2019 Alan Fairbourn Memorial Prize for Most Meritorious Final Year Project for master's dissertation entitled, "Transportweet2 Real-time public transport service analytics sourced from social media via practical application of Natural Language Processing & Machine Learning".

Snippets

Personal Website @ steken.dev

Most recently, I've updated my personal website and blog, going from Jekyll to using ReactJS and Gatsby, which uses GraphQL to generate pages from static Markdown article files. The site is hosted at no cost on GitHub Pages, with a GitHub Actions CI pipeline for instant, easy deployments. The site features my own artwork and photography, accompanying technical articles I publish when I get some time to work on them!



More about me

I like to work with people who...

genuinely care about the product, the customers and the vision. People who are in it for the long-run, care about building a strong culture, and help each other with their learning and development.

I'm excited to work for a fast-growing company because...

I haven't worked anywhere else! I like being able to jump in anywhere I'm needed, picking new skills up on the fly, working with new people and teams every day, and fixing things as we go.

Languages spoken

Japanese

I want to work for a company that...

has solved, or will solve, a real problem (good product-market fit) whatever the industry or domain – with kind, intelligent, curious and ethical people from a multitude of backgrounds and cultures.

Interests

I love travelling, meeting people and experiencing different cultures, languages, customs and cuisine. I enjoy being curious, learning and reading. I'm pretty into strength training, too!